Shoshana is a thriller, romance, history film directed by Michael Winterbottom.
In this edge-of-your-seat thriller inspired by real events, a British police officer and a
Jewish woman fall in love amidst the political turmoil of 1930s Tel Aviv.
With British control over Palestine precarious and conflict
inevitable, everyone is forced to choose a side.
Thomas Wilkin, played by Douglas Booth.
Geoffrey Morton, played by Harry Melling.
Shoshana Borochov, played by Irina Starshenbaum.
Alice Morton, played by Gina Bramhill.
Avraham Stern, played by Aury Alby.
Luba Borochov, played by Liudmyla Vasylieva.
Shoshana is a 2023 British biographical thriller
film directed by Michael Winterbottom.
The film is set in 1930s/1940s British Mandatory Palestine.
It follows the tragic love story of Shoshana Borochov (Irina Starshenbaum), daughter of one of the founders of socialist
Zionism, and British police officer Tom Wilkin (Douglas Booth), while Wilkin and fellow police officer Geoffrey J.
Morton (Harry Melling) hunt for Zionist militant Avraham Stern (Aury Alby).
The film explores themes of tel aviv, israel, zionism, based on
true story, english police, political thriller.
The tone is emotional and intense.